Guide to the Office of the President records, 1795-2007 RG0002
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Cloyd Heck Marvin records, 1903, 1924-1969; 1927-1959; Series 2; 17.25 Linear Feet 34 document boxes, 1 slim document box
  - University organization files, 1903, 1930-1957, and undated; Series 2 Sub-series 5; 9.25 Linear Feet 19.5 document boxes
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Inter-American Center, General, undated (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Law School, General, 1936-1957; 3 folder(s) (Box 35, Folder 1, Folder 2, Folder 3)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Law School, Continuing Legal Education, undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Law School, Degrees and Curriculum, undated (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Law School, Law Review, undated (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Law School, National University, undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Law School, Proposed Public Law Research Center, 1945-1959 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Law School, Segregation, undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Law School, Washington College of Law, undated (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Law School, Gifts, undated (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Patent, Trade Mark and Copyright Foundation, General, 1949-1956 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Patent, Trade Mark and Copyright Foundation, History of Establishment, undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Patent, Trade Mark and Copyright Foundation, Advisory Council and Honorary Members, undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Patent, Trade Mark and Copyright Foundation, Budget, undated (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Law Center, General, 1945-1948 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Law Center, Fund Drive, 1951-1957 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Law Center, Alumni Correspondence with President Marvin, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Law Center, Trip to West Coast, October-November 1954 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Law Center, Fund Drive Publications, undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Library, General, 1935-1957 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Library Science, School of, undated (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Library, Carnegie Endowment for International Peace Library, undated (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Library, Gifts, undated (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, General, 1933-1950; 2 folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 8, Folder 9)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, National University Medical School, Merger, 1903 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, Medical School and Hospital Property, 1335 H Street, undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, Medical School Organization, 1928-31 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, Theobald Smith Medal, undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, New Dean of School of Medicine, 1938-39 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, Post Graduate Courses, 1946-57 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, Kellog Foundation, 1943-52 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, ROTC Unit, 1951-53 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, Medical School Survey teaching Loads and Services - includes research, 1953 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, Medical Research Building, 1953-1956 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, Medical School Building, 1954 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, Finances and Problems, 1953-54 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, Federal Rehabiliation Center Proposal, 1955 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, National Fund for Medical Education, undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, Commonwealth fund, 1956 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, Gifts, 1953-1957 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - General File, Deanship of Medical School - Advisory Committee, 1957 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - Departments, Anatomy, undated (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - Departments, Anesthesiology, undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - Departments, Bacteriology, Hygiene and Preventative Medicine, undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - Departments, Bacteriology, Biochemistry, undated (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - Departments, Medicine, undated (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - Departments, Neurology and Neurological Surgery, undated (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - Departments, Obstetrics and Gynecology, undated (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - Departments, Pathology, undated (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - Departments, Pediatrics, undated (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - Departments, Pharmacology, undated (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - Departments, Otolaryngology, undated (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - Departments, Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, undated (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - Departments, Physiology, undated (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - Departments, Radiology, undated (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Medicine - Departments, Surgery, undated (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Men's Activities, General, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 5)
      Contains one memo related to an automobile accident in which two students were killed.
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Personnel Department, General, 1948-57 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, School of Pharmacy, General, 1936-57 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Registrar, General, 1935-57 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Registrar, Accelerated Program, undated (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Registrar, Diplomas and Convocation, undated (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Registrar, Degrees, undated (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Registrar, Grading System, undated (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Registrar, Theses, undated (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Registrar, Students Not Premitted to Register, undated (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Research, General, 1959 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Research, Grants, 1943-1957; 2 folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 16, Folder 17)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Research, National Foundation for Infant Paralysis, undated (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Research, Research Grants - American Cancer & Damon Runyon Research, 1948-57 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Research, Rockefeller Foundation for Dr. Du Vigneaud, 1935-1938 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Research, Research Report by Dr. Vigneaud, 1938 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Research, Relation of Government to Research, undated (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, ROTC, General, 1951-1956; 2 folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 4, Folder 5)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, ROTC, Application for Acceptance of AFROTC Unit at GWU, 1950 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, ROTC, Appointment of Property Custodian (Charles A. Billman), undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, ROTC, Curriculm, undated (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, ROTC, Women's Squadron, undated (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Division of Special Students, General, undated (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Summer Sessions, General, 1937-56 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Summer Sessions, University Division: Dean Allee, Asst. I.B. Bittansen, undated (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Testing and Counseling, Veterans Contract for Vocational Advisement, undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Testing and Counseling, Testing and Counseling Center, undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Testing and Counseling, Freshman Intelligence Tests, undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Testing and Counseling, Medicine Apptitude Tests, undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Treasurer, General, 1935-1939 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Treasurer, Comptroller, 1934-1943 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Treasurer, General, 1944-1955 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Treasurer, University Auditors, undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Treasurer, Riggs Loan, 1934-1937 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Treasurer, Financial Information, 1952 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Treasurer, Securities bought and sold, undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Treasurer, Fees, Study of, undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Treasurer, Redevelopment - Urban Renewal Project, undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Treasurer, Redevelopment - Henery Churchill Plans, undated (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Treasurer, Redevelopment - President Marvin's Plans for developing university site, undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, University Development - Assistant to the President, General, 1953-1957 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, University Development - Assistant to the President, University Development Committee, 1956-1957 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, University Development - Assistant to the President, Proposed Stadium, undated (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, University Development - Assistant to the President, Fundraising, undated (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, University Development - Assistant to the President, Student Promotion, undated (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, University Development - Assistant to the President, Educational Counseling, 1949-1955 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, University Development - Assistant to the President, Public Relations - General, 1939-1957; 2 folder(s) (Box 44, Folder 1, Folder 2)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, University Development - Assistant to the President, Public Relations - TV Programs, undated (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, University Development - Assistant to the President, Public Relations - University Gazette, undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, University Development - Assistant to the President, Public Relations - View Book, 1955-1956 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, University Development - Assistant to the President, Public Relations - Public Relations National Convention, 1949 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Director of Veterans Education, General, 1943-1950 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Director of Veterans Education, Veterans Bulletin, undated (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Director of Veterans Education, Survey of Student Veterans - GWU, September 1946 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Director of Veterans Education, Registration and Enrollment, undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities - Men's, Dean of Men, Dean Bissell, undated (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities - Men's, General, 1946-1952 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities - Men's, Fraternities, 1947-1956 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities - Women's, General, 1945-1956 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities - Women's, Staughton Hall, undated (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities, Student Council, 1949-1957 (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities, Student Council - Constitution, undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities, Athletics, Men's, 1945-1957 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities, Band, undated (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities, Career Conference, undated (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities, Cherry Tree, 1931-1956 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities, Colonial Campus Club, undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities, Dramatics, 1945-1954 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities, Engineers' Council, undated (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities, Hatchet Controversey, 1939 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities, Hatchet (including constitution), 1947-1957 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities, Handbook, Student, undated (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities, Homecoming, undated (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities, Interfraternity Council, undated (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities, Library Magazine, undated (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities, Morter Board, undated (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Student Activities, Religious Organizations, undated (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Rule 6, Student Administration, undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Rule 6, Academic Freedom, undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Rule 6, American Veterans Committee, undated (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Rule 6, Case of David Carliner, undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Rule 6, Publications, Committee on, 1946-1965 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Rule 6, Liberal Club, 1929-1938 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Rule 6, Magna Charta Club, undated (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Prizes and prize tea files, 1928-1965, and undated; Series 2 Sub-series 6; 0.75 Linear Feet 1.5 document boxes
    The prizes and prize tea files were sent to the library by the office of the president in July 1980.
    The files in this sub-series are arranged in three groups, the meaning of which was likely important at the time the files were active, but is largely irrelevant today. The first set of files were organized under the heading "Recommendations requested," the second under "Non-current," and the third was an alphabetically-arranged set. Within each set, files are arranged alphabetically by prize name.
    The Prize and Prize Tea files comprise correspondence regarding the founding, administration, and awarding of various academic prizes at the university. The files are primarily from the Marvin administration, but some continue on into his successors' administrations. The sub-series also includes a file of excerpts from the Board of Trustees' minutes in which actions were taking regarding prizes.
    - Prizes - Recommendations requested: Action by the Board of Trustees, undated (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Prizes - Recommendations requested: Alpha Zeta Omega - Pharmacy, undated (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Prizes - Recommendations requested: American Pharmaceutical Association Prize, undated (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Prizes - Recommendations requested: Beta Phi Alpha, undated (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Prizes - Recommendations requested: Martin L. Cannon Memorial, undated (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Prizes - Recommendations requested: Chi Upsilon, undated (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Prizes - Recommendations requested: Colonial Dames, undated (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Prizes - Recommendations requested: George Howland Cox, undated (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - Prizes - Recommendations requested: Daughters of the American Revolution, undated (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Prizes - Recommendations requested: Harry Cassel Davis, undated (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Prizes - Recommendations requested: Willian Thornwall Davis, undated (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Prizes - Recommendations requested: Delphi, undated (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - Prizes - Recommendations requested: General, undated (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - Prizes non-current: Delta Gamma, undated (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Prizes non-current: Delta Phi Epsilon, undated (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Prizes non-current: Delta Sigma Rho, undated (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Prizes non-current: Ellsworth - Law, undated (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Prizes non-current: French Government Award, undated (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Prizes non-current: Arthur B. Heaton, undated (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Prizes non-current: Samuel Herrick, undated (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Prizes non-current: Hispanic American History, undated (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Prizes non-current: Henry E. Kalusowski, undated (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Prizes non-current: Howard Francis Kane, undated (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Prizes non-current: Kappa Delta, undated (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Prizes non-current: Medical Society, undated (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Prizes non-current: Phi Alpha, undated (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - Prizes non-current: Phi Mu, undated (Box 47, Folder 19)
    - Prizes non-current: Phi Sigma Kappa - Oratory, undated (Box 47, Folder 20)
    - Prizes non-current: Phi Sigma Sigma, undated (Box 47, Folder 21)
    - Prizes non-current: Pi Lambda Theta, undated (Box 47, Folder 22)
    - Prizes non-current: Sigma Xi, undated (Box 47, Folder 23)
    - Prizes non-current: Sigma Pi Sigma, undated (Box 47, Folder 24)
    - Prizes non-current: Theobald Smith, undated (Box 47, Folder 25)
    - Prizes non-current: United Daughters of the Confederacy, undated (Box 47, Folder 26)
    - Prizes non-current: Zeta Tau Alpha Prize - Sociology, undated (Box 47, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous: Memo transferring prize files to appropriate schools and colleges (Were transferred to Registrar's Office from President's Office in 1966), 1972 September 26 (Box 47)
    - May Day Awards: Alpha Delta Pi May Day, undated (Box 47, Folder 28)
    - Prizes A to F and G to Z: Andy Davies Awards, undated (Box 47, Folder 29)
    - Prizes A to F and G to Z: Colonel Walter G. Bryte Prize for ROTC Unit May Day, undated (Box 47, Folder 30)
    - Prizes A to F and G to Z: Delta Gamma May Day, undated (Box 47, Folder 31)
    - Prizes A to F and G to Z: Motar Board May Day, undated (Box 47, Folder 32)
    - Prizes A to F and G to Z: Old Men May Day, undated (Box 47, Folder 33)
    - Prizes A to F and G to Z: Omicron Delta Kappa May Day, undated (Box 47, Folder 34)
    - Prizes A to F and G to Z: Order of Scarlet May Day, undated (Box 47, Folder 35)
    - Prizes A to F and G to Z: Pi Beta Pi May Day, undated (Box 47, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous: Tea Procedures, undated (Box 47, Folder 37)
    - Prizes A to F and G to Z: Prize Awards Tea, 1965 (Box 47, Folder 38)
    - Prizes A to F and G to Z: Prizes not accepted, undated (Box 47, Folder 39)
    - Prizes A to F and G to Z: Prizes withdrawn or discounted - action by Board, undated (Box 47, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous files, 1927-1969; Series 2 Sub-series 7; 0.5 Linear Feet 1 document box
    The files in this sub-series are not arranged in any particular order.
    The Miscellaneous sub-series consists of files about Marvin or his administration that were accumulated by university staff other than his office, likely historians, librarians, and archivists.
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Presidents, 1927-1959 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Structure Plan, 1927-1940 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, 1930s - 1952; 3 folder(s) (Box 48, Folder 4, Folder 5, Folder 6, Folder 8)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Criticism of his administration, 1927-1959 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Cloyd H. Marvin, Death and Obituary, also Dorothy Betts Marvin, May 1, 1969 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Presidents--Marvin, Cloyd Heck (former vertical file), 1947-05/01/1969 (Box 48, Folder 10)
- Oswald Symister Colclough and Thomas Henry Carroll records, circa 1960-1965; Series 3; 0.25 Linear Feet 1 slim document box
  The Carroll files are arranged before the Colclough report, but beyond that the files are not arranged in any particular order.
  Oswald Symister Colclough twice served as acting president of The George Washington University: from 1959 to 1961 and 1964 to 1965. He was also a professor of law and Dean of the Law School from 1949-1953, Dean of Facilities from 1953-64 and Provost from 1961-64, retiring from GW in 1964.
  Colclough was born in Monroetown, Pennsylvania on November 18, 1898. He died January 26, 1981 in Chevy Chase. Maryland. Following graduation from the U.S. Naval Academy in 1920, he attended GW's Law School and received an LL.B. in 1935, receiving the John Bell Larner Medal for the highest grades in the bachelor of laws program. While at the Naval Academy, Colclough served with the Atlantic Fleet in World War I. In 1945 he was promoted to rear admiral and in November of that year he was confirmed by the Senate as Judge Advocate General of the Navy. During World War II he commanded submarines for the North Pacific Fleet, later serving as commanding officer of the battleship North Carolina. He retired from active military service in 1950 with the rank of vice admiral.
  Admiral Colclough was active in professional and public service roles in the law, defense policy, education and government throughout his academic, legal and military careers. He was a member of the U.S. delegation to the United Nations Conference on Law of the Sea in 1958 and 1960, Chairman of the White House Disarmament Task Force on Navy Inspection, 1955-1958, and Director of the Patent, Trademark, and Copyright Research Institute at GW, among other positions. In 1961 GW awarded him an honorary degree as Doctor of Science.
  Thomas Henry Carroll, George Washington University's thirteenth president, served from 1961 to 1964. Carroll was a specialist in economics and business administration, and served seven years as Vice President of the Ford Foundation before assuming the Presidency of the University. He was born May 12, 1914 in San Francisco, and earned a B.S. degree from the University of California (1934). Dr. Carroll earned M.B.A. (1936) and Doctor of Commercial Science (1939) degrees from Harvard University. From 1939-1942 he was a faculty member and assistant dean of the Harvard Graduate School of Business Administration, the latter at the age of twenty-six.
  After serving in World War II, he was dean of the University of North Carolina's School of Business Administration from 1950-1954. Dr. Carroll began work with the Ford Foundation in 1946, when he agreed to serve on an advisory committee on policy and programs. He later became director of economic development and administration before taking over as vice president of the Foundation in 1954. President John F. Kennedy spoke at his inauguration, receiving an honorary degree from the alma mater of his wife Jacqueline, class of 1951. In his remarks President Kennedy said, "My wife beat me to this honor by eight or nine years. It took her two years to get a degree, and it took me two minutes; but in any case, we are both grateful."